<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<addonCore>
  <label>SoRoSim</label>
  <version>6.3</version>
  <type>Toolbox</type>
  <identifier>5b6a8031-ad6c-43de-a924-3a4a63d06319</identifier>
  <summary>A Unified simulation and analysis platform for soft, rigid and hybrid robotic systems</summary>
  <description>This is a MATLAB toolbox that uses the Geometric Variable Strain (GVS) approach to provide a unified framework for the modeling, analysis, and control of soft, rigid, and hybrid robots.The toolbox can be used to analyze open-, closed- and branched structures and allows the user to model many different external loading and actuation scenarios. Soft links should be modelled as a Cosserat rod, a 1D, slender rod accounting for bend, twist, stretch, and shear DoFs. While rigid links can have any shape. The Toolbox GUI assists with the creation of links, their assembly, assignment of DoFs, and the application of external and actuation forces.  
The examples folder of the toolbox contains some saved linkages and links you can run simulations for.
This toolbox gives the user access to object properties and functions thus allowing for use alongside custom codes to perform various analyses such as design optimization, control and others.
Find the overview of the toolbox, validation, and examples of problems that can be analized using SoRoSim in our IEEE Robotics and Automation Magazine paper, "SoRoSim: A MATLAB Toolbox for Hybrid Rigid-Soft Robots Based on the Geometric Variable-Strain Approach" https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9895355 or https://doi.org/10.1109/MRA.2022.3202488
More details about the theory behind the toolbox and some of its applications can be found on: https://arxiv.org/abs/2107.05494
This work was supported in part by US Office of Naval Research Global under Grant N62909-21-1-2033, and in part by the the Khalifa University of Science and Technology under Grants CIRA-2020-074, RC1-2018-KUCARS</description>
  <createdBy name="Ikhlas Ben Hmida"/>
  <image>resources/screenshot.png</image>
</addonCore>
